# JACOB GIBSON

IT systems master student

## PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am an IT professional motivated to improve the whole organisation's performance through better IT systems that work for day-to-day operations. I have expertise in a range of operating systems, hardware and software. I especially enjoy applying novel artificial intelligence (AI) approaches to enhance existing systems. The world of computing and IT systems especially thrill me. I would to share this passion as part of your team in the future.

E-mail

gibson.jacob.d@gmail.com

Mobile

07990 277384

**Address** 

65 Ednaston Rd Nottingham NG7 2JF

#### SKILLS

LANGUAGES		
Python and Java		
SQL Databases		
Azure Al		
Windows and Linux systems	_	
IT Troubleshooting		

# HOBBIES

English

French

Volleyball, design, outdoors and hiking, music and concerts, reading

## **EDUCATION**

## 2:1 MSc Cloud and Enterprise Computing

Nottingham Trent University

2020 - 2021

Key skills gained:

- Learning to design and manage Enterprise-level IT systems
- Using AI / Machine Learning algorithms to improve or automate business processes and practices
- Overseeing the adoption of Cloud Systems for businesses
- Managing the security of computer networks and Cloud Systesm
- Integrating best IT practices into the firm's operations
- Software engineering

#### 2:1 BA (Hons) Computing

Nottingham Trent University

2016 - 2020

Notable modules: Information Systems Management, Artificial Intelligence, Business Analysis, Information and Database Engineering, Information Security

## **Tapton Secondary School**

\_\_\_ 2014 - 2016

A-level passes in three subjects: Business Studies (A), Maths (B) and English Literature (B)

# Tapton Secondary School

2009 - 2014

11 GCSEs, grade A\*-C including Maths and English

# JACOB GIBSON

IT systems master student

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Placement year in IT divis	ior
----------------------------	-----

ASOS - Online fashion retailer, London \_\_\_\_ 2018 - 2019

- Implementing AI knowledge mining solutions with Azure AI
- Using tools for Al conversational solutions with firm clients
- Supporting the development and launch of new iPad/iPhone customer app
- Processing tickets related to software and hardware challenges
- · Identifying and resolving network issues
- Optimising website performance using SEO
- Managing website content and e-mail marketing

# 3-month summer IT internship

Drivy - Carsharing app provider, London \_\_\_\_ 2017

- Addressing employees' tech issues related to hardware and software
- Updating and maintaining virus protection software
- Configuring wide area networks (WAN) or local area networks (LAN)
- Installing new hardware and software systems or components
- Performing routine maintenance or standard repairs to networking components or equipment

# **ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE**

## Online courses

- Neural Networks and Deep Learning (on coursera.org)
- Google IT Automation with Python Professional Certificate (on coursera.org)
- System Administratio and IT Infrastructure Systems (on coursera.org)
- Python for Data Science (on edX.org)

### Youth club volunteer

M8S Youth Club, Nottingham \_\_\_ 2017 - today

Helping children with learning disabilities and supporting them in activities such as indoor and outdoor games, cooking, reading, and on outings like hiking trips, bowling or canoeing

## **REFERENCES**

References will be provided upon request